Lesson 10. The loss of the Titanic. The great ship, Titanic, sailed for New York from South
第10课。失去泰坦尼克号。泰坦尼克号的大船从南方航行
Hampton on April 10, 1912. She was carrying 1,316 passengers and crew of 891. Even by modern
汉普顿于1912年4月10日。她载有1,316名乘客和891的乘员。
colossal: adj. 庞大的
standards, the 46,000-ton Titanic was a colossal ship. At the time, however, she was not only
标准，46,000吨的泰坦尼克号是一艘巨大的船。但是，当时她不仅是
the largest ship that had ever been built, but was regarded as unsinkable. For she had 16
有史以来最大的船，但被认为是不可接受的。因为她有16
watertight: adj. 不漏水的, compartment: n.  （轮船的）密封舱, flood: v.   充满水, float: v.   漂浮，飘浮
watertight compartments. Even if two of these were flooded, she would still be able to float.
水密隔室。即使其中两个被淹没了，她仍然可以漂浮。
tragic: adj. 悲惨的, liner: n.   班船
The tragic sinking of this great liner will always be remembered. For she went down on her
这个伟大的衬里的悲惨沉没将永远被记住。因为她跌倒了
voyage: n.   航行
first voyage with heavy loss of life. Four days after setting out, while the Titanic
首次航行，生命损失严重。出发四天，而泰坦尼克号
iceberg: n.   冰山
was sailing across the icy water of the North Atlantic. Huge iceberg was suddenly spotted
正驶过北大西洋的冰冷水。突然发现了巨大的冰山
lookout: n.   了望员
by a lookout. After the alarm had been given, the great ship turned sharply to avoid a direct
通过监视。发出警报后，大船急转弯以避免直接
collision: n.   碰撞, miss: v.   避开
collision. The Titanic turned just in time. Narrowly missing the immense walk of ice which
碰撞。泰坦尼克号及时地转过身。狭窄地错过了巨大的冰
slight: adj. 轻微的
rose over 100 feet out of the water beside her. Suddenly, there was a slight trembling
从她旁边的水中升起超过100英尺。突然，有一点颤抖
sound from below. And the captain went down to see what had happened. The noise had been
从下方发出声音。船长下来看看发生了什么。噪音已经
faint: adj. 微弱的
so faint that no one though that the ship had been damaged. Below, the captain realized
如此微弱，以至于没有人损坏了这艘船。下面，船长意识到
watertight: adj. 不漏水的, compartment: n.  （轮船的）密封舱, horror: n.   恐惧
to his horror that the Titanic was sinking rapidly. For five of her 16 watertight compartments
令他惊讶的是，泰坦尼克号正在迅速下沉。她的16个水密隔室中的五个
flood: v.   充满水, abandon: v.   抛弃, plunge: v.   投入，跳入
had already been flooded. The order to abandon ship was given and hundreds of people plunged
已经被淹没了。放弃船只的命令被降低了
lifeboat: n.   救生船
into the icy water. As there were not enough lifeboats for everybody, 1,500 lives were lost.
进入冰冷的水。由于每个人都没有足够的救生艇，因此1,500人丧生。